John Karas

Santa Ana, CA 92701 jkaras@jkaras.net 805-570-4528

Experienced Senior Technical Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the medical device industry. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Sales, Data Center, Management, and Software Documentation. Strong information technology professional with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Information Systems from the State University of New York.

Work Experience

Senior Technical User Support Analyst

Medtronic - Santa Ana, CA 2014 to Present

- Manage all IT operations at office, design, and manufacturing facility of surgical healthcare technologies.
- Administer the local network, including active directory and file servers. Maintain and troubleshoot physical network including switching and routing hardware as well as wireless access points and connectivity.
- Responsible for inventory, deployment and e-waste of all IT hardware and infrastructure for the site.
- Provide remote and local end-user IT support to over 800 computers and 400 end users related to a broad spectrum of IT infrastructure and applications. PC-hardware, smartphones, Xerox multifunction printers, office applications, productivity tools, client operating systems and internet applications.
- Coordinate communication and troubleshooting to determine impact of major system outages which affect the entire organization.
- Creates and updates knowledge base articles to provide a good level of service for end-users. Acts as knowledge champion to share knowledge across IT teams.
- Able to independently inventory and image hardware, software and IT related products or systems. Responsible for monitoring and maintaining accurate IT asset information as required.
- · Administers accounts and access on various platforms in a corporate environment
- Operate in a clean-room environment to support sensitive healthcare production within approved FDA quality guidelines.
 - Utilizes ServiceNow CRM to receive, update, and respond to end user requests on a daily basis.
- Supports migration of userbase to OneDrive backup solution for local user computers as well as instructs and advised customer use of OneDrive.
 - Assists with SCCM software instalations in Windows 10 Enterprise environment.
 - Configures and troubleshoots print queues and ports on virtual Windows 2016 Servers.
 - Updates and maintains SharePoint documents and articles relating to company practices and procedures.
 - Install and support MS Office 365 for userbase as well as troubleshoot single-sign on protocols for user login.

Senior Support Engineer

Sonos - Santa Barbara, CA 2012 to 2014

- Respond directly to support issues and service requests submitted via, telephone, email, web, text chat, and voicemail
- Identify, recreate, resolve, or escalate issues using existing guidelines and standardized tools. Troubleshoot customer WANs/LANs and enterprise level networks. Windows, Mac OSX, Android, and iOS
- Utilizing proper CRM tools and systems, demonstrate customer relations skills, and maintain a positive company image.

IT Consultant Entrusted

Services - Goleta, CA 2011 to 2012

- •Daily travel to client sites to resolve network and workstation issues
- •Support for both Apple and PC based workstations and servers
- •Conduct remote support sessions over the internet and support phone calls to provide IT solutions to clients

Technical Account Manager

Yardi Systems - Santa Barbara, CA 2010 to 2011

Implement and support web based database applications.

- Daily contact with customers both via e-mail or telephone.
- Provide appropriate level support to the customer and escalate issues when needed.
- Implement and maintain schedules for upgrades or new application capabilities and provide training or assistance in initial use of the software.
- Employ tools such as GoToMeeting, Word and Excel, SQL editor

Lead Technical Support Impulse Internet

Services - Santa Barbara, CA 2008 to 2010

Answer incoming phone and e-mail support requests.

- Use a ticketing system to resolve or escalate issues to appropriate department.
- Troubleshoot both network and end user computer issues to get users back online.
- Configure Outlook, Thunderbird, and Apple Mail for e-mail access.
- Manage enterprise level network hardware at the ISP level
- Configure, manage and troubleshoot VoIP phone systems

Supervisor / Systems Administrator Ommi Computer

Information Management - Goleta, CA 2003 to 2008

Support and manage a team of 40 employees to meet sales goals on a daily basis.

• Maintained the technical infrastructure for company, desktops, printers, faxes and network.

Education

Bachelor's in Information Systems State

University of New York - Springs, NY 2018

Associate in Computer Information Systems Santa

Barbara City College - Santa Barbara, CA 2008

Associate in Communications Santa Barbara

City College - Santa Barbara, CA 2005

Skills

- Windows (10+ years)
- Networking (10+ years)
- Management (5 years)
- Microsoft Windows Server

Additional Information

SKILLS PROFILE

- Effective and knowledgeable in the use of Microsoft Office
- Supported users both over the phone and the use of remote access
- Proficient in the use of a multiline phone system
- Proven record of meeting sales or project goals
- Able to work both independently or within a team environment
- · Good customer-relations background

Additional Technical Skills: Support networks and PC's using Windows XP, Vista, Windows 7 and 10 operating systems. Removed spyware and secured computers with anti-virus and firewall software. Use of Wireshark to troubleshoot network issues. Proficient in Open Office, Filezila, 7-zip, PsPad, VMware. Adobe Photoshop, Acrobat, MS Office Suite, TCP/IP, FTP. Router LAN/WAN and WiFi config. Experience with Cisco OS, Adtran routers/ switches at enterprise level.